
var quiz = {
  "JS": [
  {
  "id": 1,
  "question": "What killed Princess Diana?",
  "options": [
  {
  "a": "A car crash",
  "b": "Her driver",
  "c": "Old age",
  "d": "Cancer"
  }
  ],
  "answer": "A car crash",
  "score": 0,
  "status": ""
  },
  {
  "id": 2,
  "question": "What is the highest grossing film of all time",
  "options": [
  {
  "a": "Avatar",
  "b": "Black Panther",
  "c": "Game of thrones",
  "d": "Avengers: End game"
  }
  ],
  "answer": "Avatar",
  "score": 0,
  "status": ""
  },
  {
  "id": 3,
  "question": "Who has the most grammys ever?",
  "options": [
  {
  "a": "Adele",
  "b": "Sia",
  "c": "Beyonce",
  "d": "2pac"
  }
  ],
  "answer": "Beyonce",
  "score": 0,
  "status": ""
  },
  {
  "id": 4,
  "question": "Which artist won the most grammy's in one night",
  "options": [
  {
  "a": "2pac",
  "b": "Micheal Jackson",
  "c":"Beyonce",
  "d":"Adele"

  }
  ],
  "answer": "Micheal Jackson",
  "score": 0,
  "status": ""
  },
  {
  "id": 5,
  "question": "Which streaming platform created Stranger Things",
  "options": [
  {
  "a": "Netflix",
  "b": "Paramount",
  "c": "Peacock",
  "d": "Disney",
  }
  ],
  "answer": "Netflix",
  "score": 0,
  "status": ""
  },
  {
  "id": 6,
  "question": "Who sang Rolling deep",
  "options": [
  {
  "a": "The Beatles",
  "b": "Adele",
  "c": "Declan McKenna",
  "d": "Beyonce"
  }
  ],
  "answer": "Adele",
  "score": 0,
  "status": ""
  },
  {
  "id": 7,
  "question": "What was the first animated feature film produced by Disney?",
  "options": [
  {
  "a": "Mickey Mouse",
  "b": "Snow White",
  "c": "Cinderella",
  "d": "The Lion King"
  }
  ],
  "answer": "Snow White",
  "score": 0,
  "status": ""
  },
  {
  "id": 8,
  "question": "Which movie features the quote, May the Force be with you",
  "options": [
  {
  "a": "Guardians of the galaxy",
  "b": "Star Wars",
  "c": "Merlin",
  "d": "Black Panther",
  }
  ],
  "answer": "Star Wars",
  "score": 0,
  "status": ""
  },
  {
  "id": 9,
  "question": "Adam Levine is in which musical band?",
  "options": [
  {
  "a": "Maroon 5",
  "b": "The beatles",
  "c": "BTS",
  "d": "None of the above."
  }
  ],
  "answer": "Maroon 5",
  "score": 0, 
  "status": ""
  },
  {
  "id": 10,
  "question": "Who starred as Jack in the movie Titanic?",
  "options": [
  {
  "a": "Adam Sandler ",
  "b": "Leonardo DiCaprio",
  "c": "Will Smith",
  "d": "Jack Griffo",
  }
  ],
  "answer": "Leonardo DiCaprio",
  "score": 0,
  "status": ""
  },
  {
  "id": 11,
  "question": "What is the name of Taylor Swift's first album",
  "options": [
  {
  "a": "Taylor Swift",
  "b": "Scarlet",
  "c": "yes and?",
  "d": "Queen"
  }
  ],
  "answer": "Taylor Swift",
  "score": 0,
  "status": ""
  },
  {
  "id": 12,
  "question": "What TV show is known for the characters Ross, Rachel, Monica, Chandler, Joey, and Phoebe?",
  "options": [
  {
  "a": "FRIENDS",
  "b": "How i met your mother",
  "c": "Bel-air",
  "d": "Bob hearts Abishola"
  }
  ],
  "answer": "FRIENDS",
  "score": 0,
  "status": ""
  },
  {
  "id": 13,
  "question": "What is the name of the kingdom where Elsa and Anna live in Frozen?",
  "options": [
  {
  "a": "Buckingham",
  "b": "Arandelle",
  "c": "Fillmore",
  "d": "Metroville"
  }
  ],
  "answer": "Arandelle", 
  "score": 0,
  "status": ""
  },
  {
  "id": 14,
  "question": " Which singer is known for the album 21?",
  "options": [
  {
  "a": "21 Savage",
  "b": "Adele",
  "c": "Beyonce",
  "d":"Sasha Sloane "
  }
  ],
  "answer": "Adele",
  "score": 0,
  "status": ""
  },
  {
  "id": 15,
  "question": "Which famous pop star's fans are called Little Monster?",
  "options": [
  {
  "a": "Olivia Rodrigo",
  "b": "Lady Gaga",
  "c": "Nicki Minaj",
  "d": "Lil Uzi Vert"
  }
  ],
  "answer": "Lady Gaga",
  "score": 0,
  "status": ""
  },
  {
  "id": 16,
  "question": "What is the name of the ice planet in Star Wars: The Empire Strikes Back?",
  "options": [
  {
  "a": "Hoth",
  "b": "Starville",
  "c": "Arandelle",
  "d": "Wakanda"
  }
  ],
  "answer": "Hoth",
  "score": 0,
  "status": ""
  },
  {
  "id": 17,
  "question": "What is the name of Batman's butler?",
  "options": [
  {
  "a": " Alfred Pennyworth.",
  "b": "Greg",
  "c": "Topper",
  "d": "Craige"
  }
  ],
  "answer": " Alfred Pennyworth.",
  "score": 0,
  "status": ""
  },
  {
  "id": 18,
  "question": "Who played Jack Sparrow in the Pirates of the Caribbean series?",
  "options": [
  {
  "a": "Tom Holland",
  "b": "Johnny Depp",
  "c": "Theo James",
  "d": "Chris Evans"
  }
  ],
  "answer": "Johnny Depp",
  "score": 0,
  "status": ""
  },
  {
  "id": 19,
  "question": " What is the name of the dragon in Disney's Mulan?",
  "options": [
  {
  "a": "Mushu",
  "b": "Miranda",
  "c":"Mulan",
  "d":"Greg"
  }
  ],
  "answer": "Mushu",
  "score": 0,
  "status": ""
  },
  {
  "id": 20,
  "question": " In Game of Thrones, what is the name of Arya Stark's sword?",
  "options": [
  {
  "a": "Needle",
  "b": "Magna",
  "c": "Clinton",
  "d": "Little Dragon"
  }
  ],
  "answer": "Needle",
  "score": 0,
  "status": ""
  },
  {
  "id": 21,
  "question": "Who played the role of the Genie in Aladdin?",
  "options": [
  {
  "a": "Will Smith",
  "b": "Chris Evans",
  "c": "Zendaya",
  "d": "Dwayne THE ROCK Johnson"
  }
  ],
  "answer": "Will Smith",
  "score": 0,
  "status": ""
  },
  {
  "id": 22,
  "question": "What is the name of Elon Musk's electric car company?",
  "options": [
  {
  "a": "X",
  "b": "Meta",
  "c": "Tesla",
  "d": "Musk"
  }
  ],
  "answer": "Tesla",
  "score": 0,
  "status": ""
  },
  {
  "id": 23,
  "question": "Who was the voice of the disney animated character Maui",
  "options": [
  {
  "a": "Dwayne Johnson",
  "b": "Kevin Hart",
  "c": "Johnny Depp",
  "d": "None of the above"
  }
  ],
  "answer": "Dwayne Johnson",
  "score": 0,
  "status": ""
  },
  {
  "id": 24,
  "question": "Which Nigerian artist won the Grammy Award for Best Global Music Album in 2021?",
  "options": [
  {
  "a": "Davido",
  "b": "Burna Boy",
  "c": "Yemi Alade",
  "d": "Wizkid"
  }
  ],
  "answer": "Burna Boy",
  "score": 0,
  "status": ""
  },
  {
  "id": 25,
  "question": " What reality TV show did Cardi B first gain fame from?",
  "options": [
  {
  "a": "Love and HipHop",
  "b": "Keeping up with the Kardashians",
  "c": "The strip club",
  "d": "Cardi and friends"
  }
  ],
  "answer": "Love and HipHop",
  "score": 0,
  "status": ""
  }
  ]
  }
  var quizApp = function () {
  this.score = 0;
  this.qno = 1;
  this.currentque = 0;
  var totalque = quiz.JS.length;
  this.displayQuiz = function (cque) {
  this.currentque = cque;
  if (this.currentque < totalque) {
  $("#tque").html(totalque);
  $("#previous").attr("disabled", false);
  $("#next").attr("disabled", false);
  $("#qid").html(quiz.JS[this.currentque].id + '.');
  $("#question").html(quiz.JS[this.currentque].question);
  $("#question-options").html("");
  for (var key in quiz.JS[this.currentque].options[0]) {
  if (quiz.JS[this.currentque].options[0].hasOwnProperty(key)) {
  $("#question-options").append(
  "<div class='form-check option-block'>" +
  "<label class='form-check-label'>" +
  "<input type='radio' class='form-check-input' name='option' id='q" + key + "' value='" + quiz.JS[this.currentque].options[0][key] + "'><span id='optionval'>" +
  quiz.JS[this.currentque].options[0][key] +
  "</span></label>"
  );
  }
  }
  }
  if (this.currentque <= 0) {
  $("#previous").attr("disabled", true);
  }
  if (this.currentque >= totalque) {
  $('#next').attr('disabled', true);
  for (var i = 0; i < totalque; i++) {
  this.score = this.score + quiz.JS[i].score;
  }
  return this.showResult(this.score);
  }
  }
  this.showResult = function (scr) {
  $("#result").addClass('result');
  $("#result").html("<h1 class='res-header'>Total Score: &nbsp;" + scr + '/' + totalque + "</h1>");
  for (var j = 0; j < totalque; j++) {
  var res;
  if (quiz.JS[j].score == 0) {
  res = '<span class="wrong">' + quiz.JS[j].score + '</span><i class="fa fa-remove c-wrong"></i>';
  } else {
  res = '<span class="correct">' + quiz.JS[j].score + '</span><i class="fa fa-check c-correct"></i>';
  }
  $("#result").append(
  '<div class="result-question"><span>Q ' + quiz.JS[j].id + '</span> &nbsp;' + quiz.JS[j].question + '</div>' +
  '<div><b>Correct answer:</b> &nbsp;' + quiz.JS[j].answer + '</div>' +
  '<div class="last-row"><b>Score:</b> &nbsp;' + res +
  '</div>'
  );
  }
  }
  this.checkAnswer = function (option) {
  var answer = quiz.JS[this.currentque].answer;
  option = option.replace(/</g, "&lt;") //for <
  option = option.replace(/>/g, "&gt;") //for >
  option = option.replace(/"/g, "&quot;")
  if (option == quiz.JS[this.currentque].answer) {
  if (quiz.JS[this.currentque].score == "") {
  quiz.JS[this.currentque].score = 1;
  quiz.JS[this.currentque].status = "correct";
  }
  } else {
  quiz.JS[this.currentque].status = "wrong";
  }
  }
  this.changeQuestion = function (cque) {
  this.currentque = this.currentque + cque;
  this.displayQuiz(this.currentque);
  }
  }
  var jsq = new quizApp();
  var selectedopt;
  $(document).ready(function () {
  jsq.displayQuiz(0);
  $('#question-options').on('change', 'input[type=radio][name=option]', function (e) {
  //var radio = $(this).find('input:radio');
  $(this).prop("checked", true);
  selectedopt = $(this).val();
  });
  });
  $('#next').click(function (e) {
  e.preventDefault();
  if (selectedopt) {
  jsq.checkAnswer(selectedopt);
  }
  jsq.changeQuestion(1);
  });
  $('#previous').click(function (e) {
  e.preventDefault();
  if (selectedopt) {
  jsq.checkAnswer(selectedopt);
  }
  jsq.changeQuestion(-1);
  });
  resultDiv.innerHTML += '<button id="restart">Restart Quiz</button>';
  document.getElementById('restart').addEventListener('click', this.restartQuiz.bind(this));
